Guide to the Maurice Sterne Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1915-1962; Series I; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  - Hall Brothers (Hallmark Cards), 1949-1956 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1917-1942 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hawaiian Pineapple Company, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Haydn, Hiram
    See: American Scholar, Box 1, folder 7
    See: Atheneum, Box 1, folder 11
    See: Bobbs-Merrill Company, Box 1, folder 17
    See: Random House, Box 3, folder 89
  - Heyman, David, 1955-1962 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Hirschl and Adler Galleries, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Hochschild, Mary, 1955-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Hollis, Howard C., 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Horwitz, Lea, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "J" general, 1939-1960 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Jacques Seligmann and Co., Inc., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "K" general, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Kahn, Virginia, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Kallen, Homer M., 1939-1957 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Knoedler and Company, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1936-1960 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - "L" general, 1937-1958 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Lewisohn, Margaret, 1950-1954, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Lewisohn, Marjorie, 1954-1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Lewisohn, Samuel, 1927-1950 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Liebes, Dorothy W., 1942-1957 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1916-1917, undated (Box 3, Folder 59-65)
  - "M" general, 1917-1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Marie Harriman Gallery, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Mayerson, Charlotte, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Milch Galleries, 1936-1963 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 1938-1953 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1933-1958 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - "N" general, 1919-1957 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - N. W. Ayer and Son, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - National Academy of Design, 1936-1957 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1946-1957 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - New Haven Jewish Community Center, 1957, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - New School for Social Research, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - The New Yorker, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Noyes, Carleton, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - "O" general, 1957-1959, undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - "P" general, 1933-1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Paci, Anthony, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Paintings of the Year (Pepsi-Cola), 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Pascin, Jules, undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1939-1955 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Phillips Memorial Gallery (Duncan Phillips), 1940-1957 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Public Buildings Administration
    See: United States Treasury Department, Box 4, folder 114
  - "R" general, 1916-1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Random House, Inc., 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Reader's Digest, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Richards, Helen, 1940-1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Riordan, Thomas D., 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Rowan, Edward B., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - "S" general, 1919-1957 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Saint-Gaudens, Homer
    See: Carnegie Institute, Box 1, folder 24
  - San Francisco Art Association, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1935, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Schmid, Ella, 1954-1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Seligman, Eustace, 1951-1957 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Shore Studio Galleries, 1948-1963 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Sohn, Karli, 1947-1948, undated (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Sopher, Beruch, 1938-1941 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Stein, Fred, 1938-1948 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Stein, Leo, 1930-1945 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Stewart, Louis
    See: Box 29, folder 503
  - Stone, Harlan Fiske, 1939-1940, undated (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Sterne, Vera, 1915-1954, undated (Box 4, Folder 105-06)
  - Sulzberger, Marion, 1947-1957 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Szold and Brandwen, 1955-1962, undated (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - "T" general, 1936-1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Thannhauser, Justin Thannhauser, Kate, 1946-1961, undated (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Train, Helen, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Ulman, Elinor, undated (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - United States Treasury Department, 1933-1941 (Box 4, Folder 114-20)
  - "V" general, 1933-1957 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - "W" general, 1931-1960, undated (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Wallace, Bob
  - Watson, Forbes, 1935-1957 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1940-1956 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Wildenstein and Company, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Wolman, Samuel Wolman, Adele, 1948-1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - "Y" general, 1945-1955 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - YKUF Art Section, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Young, Stark, 1947-1954, undated (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - "Z" general, 1930-1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Ziegner, Herman P., 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 4, Folder 132-35)
- Writings, 1919-1957; Series II; 5; (11 boxes)
  The material in Series II, Writings, is arranged alphabetically under the headings Autobiography, Essays, Notebooks, and Subject Files. Arrangement within the subseries Autobiography is chronological; arrangement within the subseries Essays and Subject Files is alphabetical by title or subject.
  - AUTOBIOGRAPHY
    - Outline, undated (Box 5, Folder 136-37)
    - Introduction, undated (Box 5, Folder 138-42)
    - 1878: Childhood in Libau, undated (Box 5, Folder 143-47)
    - 1878: Childhood in Libau, undated (Box 6, Folder 148-51)
    - 1885: Visit to Vilna, undated (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - 1885-89: Childhood in Moscow, undated (Box 6, Folder 153-54)
    - 1889: Journey to America, undated (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - 1889-94: Early Years in New York, undated (Box 6, Folder 156-58)
    - 1894: Map engraving job, undated (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - 1894-1904: National Academy of Design, undated (Box 6, Folder 160-62)
    - 1899: Work in a Saloon, undated (Box 6, Folder 163-64)
    - 1900-04: Later Years in New York, undated (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - 1904-07: Gertrude and Leo Stein in Paris, undated (Box 7, Folder 166-68)
    - 1904-07: Italy, Germany (General), undated (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - 1907: Florence, undated (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - 1907-08: Greece, 1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 172-75)
    - 1908-14: Anticoli, undated (Box 7, Folder 176-77)
    - 1908-10: Rome, undated (Box 7, Folder 178-79)
    - 1909: Trip to Moscow, undated (Box 7, Folder 180-81)
    - 1910: Germany, undated (Box 8, Folder 182-83)
    - 1911: Egypt, undated (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - 1911-12: India, undated (Box 8, Folder 185-86)
    - 1912: Burma, Java, etc., undated (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - 1912-13: Bali, 1957, undated (Box 8, Folder 188-90)
    - 1914: Return to Rome, undated (Box 8, Folder 191-92)
    - 1914: Return to U.S., undated (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - 1914-19: Mabel Dodge Luhan, undated (Box 8, Folder 194-98)
    - 1918-20: U.S.A., undated (Box 9, Folder 199)
    - 1920?-25: [Back to Europe], undated (Box 9, Folder 201)
    - 1920-25: Mussolini, undated (Box 9, Folder 202)
    - 1923-25: New York, undated (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - 1928: Spain, undated (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - 1930-39: U.S.A., Mexico, Hawaii, undated (Box 9, Folder 205)
    - 1940-57: U.S.A., undated (Box 9, Folder 206-09)
    - Epilogue, undated (Box 9, Folder 210)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 9, Folder 211-12)
  - ESSAYS
    - "American Scholar", undated (Box 10, Folder 213)
    - "The Artist Speaks on War Memorials", 1946 (Box 10, Folder 214)
    - "The Basis of American Art" (radio address), 1933 (Box 10, Folder 215)
    - Creative Arts, undated (Box 10, Folder 216)
    - "I Become a Member of the Brass-Railed Bar", undated (Box 10, Folder 217)
    - "The Interrelation of the Artist to Life" (incomplete), 1919 (Box 10, Folder 218)
    - Lectures on Art, 1937-1938 (Box 10, Folder 219)
    - "Me Imperturbe in Wanamaker's", 1955 (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - "My First Christmas Present" (draft), undated (Box 10, Folder 221)
    - "My First Christmas Present", undated (Box 10, Folder 222)
    - "Nationalism in Art", 1932 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - "Speech on 'Nationalism in Art'", 1937 (Box 10, Folder 224)
    - "New Light on Art" (radio address), 1931 (Box 10, Folder 225)
    - "The New Society", undated (Box 10, Folder 226)
    - Trial by Ordeal, undated (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - "World War II Memorials", undated (Box 10, Folder 228)
    - Untitled Essay on Art, undated (Box 10, Folder 229)
    - Untitled Essay on Cézanne, undated (Box 10, Folder 230)
  - NOTES
    - Notebooks, 1955, undated (Box 10, Folder 231-32)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 11, Folder 233-41)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - Art
      - Abstract art, undated (Box 12, Folder 242)
      - Aesthetics, undated (Box 12, Folder 243)
      - Contemporary art, undated (Box 12, Folder 244-45)
      - Criticism and critics, undated (Box 12, Folder 246)
      - Cubism, undated (Box 12, Folder 247)
      - Definition, undated (Box 12, Folder 248)
      - Expressionism, undated (Box 12, Folder 249)
      - Form and pattern, undated (Box 12, Folder 250)
      - History, undated (Box 12, Folder 251)
      - Impressionism, undated (Box 12, Folder 252)
      - Nature and art, undated (Box 12, Folder 253)
      - Non-objective art, undated (Box 12, Folder 254)
      - Science and art, undated (Box 12, Folder 255)
      - Spatial form, undated (Box 12, Folder 256-58)
      - Tactile form, undated (Box 12, Folder 259)
      - Techniques, undated (Box 12, Folder 260)
      - Training, academics, undated (Box 12, Folder 261)
      - Visual and aural art, undated (Box 12, Folder 262)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 13, Folder 263-68)
    - Art critics, undated (Box 13, Folder 269)
    - Artists
      - Cézanne, undated (Box 13, Folder 270)
      - Matisse, undated (Box 13, Folder 271)
      - Picasso, undated (Box 13, Folder 272-73)
      - Van Gogh, undated (Box 13, Folder 274)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 13, Folder 275-76)
    - Creators and discoverers, undated (Box 13, Folder 277-78)
    - Democracy and freedom, undated (Box 13, Folder 279)
    - Friends and acquaintances, undated (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - Genius, undated (Box 14, Folder 281)
    - Indian rituals, undated (Box 14, Folder 282)
    - Individualism, undated (Box 14, Folder 283)
    - Instinct, undated (Box 14, Folder 284)
    - Judaism, 1957, undated (Box 14, Folder 285-87)
    - Music (Box 14, Folder 288)
    - National characteristics
      - America, undated (Box 14, Folder 289)
      - England, undated (Box 14, Folder 290)
      - France, undated (Box 14, Folder 291)
      - Germany, undated (Box 14, Folder 292)
      - India, undated (Box 14, Folder 293)
      - Italy, undated (Box 14, Folder 294)
      - Russia, undated (Box 14, Folder 295-99)
    - Perfectionism, undated (Box 14, Folder 300)
    - Poetry, undated (Box 14, Folder 301)
    - Psychology, undated (Box 15, Folder 302-03)
    - Religion, undated (Box 15, Folder 304-06)
    - Sex (Box 15, Folder 307)
    - Tradition, 1957, undated (Box 15, Folder 308)
    - Truth, undated (Box 15, Folder 309)
    - Zeitgeist, undated (Box 15, Folder 310)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 15, Folder 311-15)
- Family Papers, 1898-1962; Series III; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Series III, Family Papers, is alphabetically arranged by type of material.
  - Address books, undated (Box 16, Folder 316)
  - Appointment books, undated (Box 16, Folder 317-18)
  - Biographical information, 1934-1950, undated (Box 16, Folder 319-20)
  - Drawings and paintings
    - Paintings
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 504
    - Sketchbooks, undated (Box 16, Folder 321-22)
      See also: Oversize, Box 29, folder 505
    - Sketchbooks, undated (Box 17, Folder 323-26)
    - Loose sketches, undated (Box 17, Folder 327-31)
      See also: Box 29, folder 506 and various pages of Corcoran Exhibition Catalogue, Box 25, folder 447
  - Financial records
    - Checks, 1939-1947 (Box 18, Folder 332)
    - Checks, 1948-1960 (Box 19, Folder 333)
    - Income tax returns, 1940-1952 (Box 20, Folder 334-35)
    - Inventory: furniture, undated (Box 20, Folder 336)
    - Inventory: paintings, 1953, undated (Box 20, Folder 337)
    - Last wills and testaments (Maurice and Vera Sterne), 1946-1957, undated (Box 20, Folder 338)
    - Leases, 1947-1957 (Box 20, Folder 339)
    - Legal agreements, contracts, 1935-1946 (Box 20, Folder 340)
    - Shipping receipts, 1954-1962 (Box 20, Folder 341)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1959, undated (Box 20, Folder 342)
  - Professional organizations: Reports and Minutes
    - American Memorial Foundation ("Plan to Establish a Living Memorial in the City of Washington, D.C."), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 343)
    - Briarcliff Junior College (Board of Trustees), 1952 May 7 (Box 20, Folder 344)
    - Commission of Fine Arts, 1946-1947 (Box 20, Folder 345-48)
    - Commission of Fine Arts, 1948-1950 (Box 21, Folder 349-54)
    - Committee on Government and Art, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 355)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters ("Report on a National Arts Commission"), 1953 (Box 21, Folder 356)
  - Reminiscences of Vera Sterne, undated (Box 21, Folder 357)
  - Speer Memorial Controversy, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 358)
  - "Struggle for Justice" (Justice Department Murals), 1935-1938, undated (Box 21, Folder 359)
  - Miscellaneous, 1898-1937, undated (Box 21, Folder 360)
- Photographs, 1933-1948; Series IV; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series IV, Photographs, is divided into six subseries: Individuals, Places, Nature, Art, Negatives, and Miscellaneous. Arrangement within each subseries is alphabetical by name or title. Unidentified photographs are placed at the end of each section.
  - INDIVIDUALS
    - Bender, Albert
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 507
    - Deuga, Draja, undated (Box 22, Folder 361)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr., undated (Box 22, Folder 362)
    - Liebes, Dorothy [?], undated (Box 22, Folder 363)
    - Segal, Louise, undated (Box 22, Folder 364)
    - Segal, Paula [?], undated (Box 22, Folder 365-66)
    - Sterne, Maurice, undated (Box 22, Folder 367)
    - Sterne, Maurice. By Carl Van Vechten, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 368)
    - Sterne, Naomi, undated (Box 22, Folder 369)
      See also: Oversize, Box 29, folder 508
    - Sterne, Rosa [?], undated (Box 22, Folder 370)
    - Sterne, Vera, undated (Box 22, Folder 371)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 22, Folder 372-73)
      See also: Oversize, Box 29, folders 509-11
  - PLACES
    - Bali [?], undated (Box 22, Folder 374)
    - Hawaii (postcards), undated (Box 22, Folder 375)
    - India, undated (Box 22, Folder 376-78)
      See also: Oversize, Box 30, folder 517
    - India (postcards), undated (Box 22, Folder 379)
    - Italy, undated (Box 22, Folder 380)
    - Provincetown, Massachusetts [?], undated (Box 22, Folder 381)
    - Provincetown, Massachusetts (postcards), undated (Box 22, Folder 382)
    - Provincetown, Massachusetts (color slides), undated (Box 22, Folder 383)
    - Surabaya (postcards), undated (Box 22, Folder 384)
    - U.S.A. (general), undated (Box 22, Folder 385)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 22, Folder 386-87)
  - NATURE
    - Adams, Ansel. "Sierra Foothills", 1948 (Box 23, Folder 388)
      See also: Box 1, folder 2
    - Williams, D. [?] "Night Blooming Cereus", undated (Box 23, Folder 389)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 23, Folder 390-92)
  - ART
    - Bali sketches, undated (Box 23, Folder 393)
    - Carnegie Institute Exhibitions, 1943-1950, undated (Box 23, Folder 394-95)
    - Character sketches, undated (Box 23, Folder 396)
    - Eastern sketches, undated (Box 23, Folder 397)
    - Fairmont Park Monument, undated (Box 23, Folder 398-99)
      See also: Oversize, Box 29, folder 512
    - Justice Department murals
      - Ansel Adams photos, undated (Box 23, Folder 400-02)
        See also: Oversize, Box 31, folder 522
      - Marshall Moxom photos, undated (Box 23, Folder 403)
      - Unknown photographer, undated (Box 23, Folder 404)
        See also: Oversize, Box 30, folder 521
    - Mabel Dodge Luhan sketches, undated (Box 23, Folder 405)
    - Marine paintings, undated (Box 23, Folder 406)
    - Rogers-Kennedy Memorial, undated (Box 24, Folder 407-18)
      See also: Box 30, folders 517-19
    - Still life, undated (Box 24, Folder 419)
    - Vera Sterne sketches, undated (Box 24, Folder 420)
    - Work by others
      - Dixon, C. Untitled
        See: Box 29, folder 513
      - Van Dyke, Willard
        See: Box 29, folder 514
      - Wilkinson, Jack. Burns, Oregon P.O. Mural, undated (Box 24, Folder 421)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 24, Folder 422)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 24, Folder 423-24)
      See also: Box 29, folder 515
  - NEGATIVES
    - Negatives, undated (Box 24, Folder 425-26)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 24, Folder 427-28)
      See also: Box 29, folder 516
- Printed Material, 1912-1957; Series V; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series V, Printed Material, is divided into Ads for Art Classes, Articles, Books, Exhibition Catalogs, Museum Bulletins, Newspaper Clippings, and Miscellaneous, arranged alphabetically by title or subject within each category.
  - Ads for Sterne's Art Classes, 1931, undated (Box 25, Folder 429)
  - Articles
    - "The Artistic Pilgrimage of Maurice Sterne." The Literary Digest, 1933 March 18 (Box 25, Folder 430)
    - Birnbaum, Martin, "Maurice Sterne," The International Studio, 1912 March (Box 25, Folder 431)
    - "Current Carnegie International Exhibition," The Mirror, 1930 October 18 (Box 25, Folder 432)
    - "Current Exhibition Notes," Arts Weekly, 1932 March 11 (Box 25, Folder 433)
    - Hopper, Inslee A. "Instinct, Environment, Tradition - Maurice Sterne," The American Magazine of Art, 1936 December (Box 25, Folder 434)
    - "An Hour in the Studio of Maurice Sterne," American Artist, 1941 December (Box 25, Folder 435)
    - Kilmer, Joyce. "Develops His Art in Savage Bali," New York Times Magazine, 1915 March 21 (Box 25, Folder 436)
    - Lane, James H. "Sterne's Allegories of Justice," The Art News, 1939 December 30 (Box 25, Folder 437)
    - Morgan, Alma Deb. "Progress in Art: Maurice Sterne," The Junior League Magazine, 1930 January (Box 25, Folder 438)
    - Neumeyer, Alfred. "Hans von Merées and the Classical Doctrine in the Nineteenth Century," The Art Bulletin, 1938 (Box 25, Folder 439)
    - Phillips, Duncan. "The Place of the Arts in the World Today," A Bulletin of the Phillips Memorial Gallery, 1941 January (Box 25, Folder 440)
    - "Second Portrait of America," Limited Edition, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 441)
    - "A Survey of American Painting," special issue of The Art News, undated (Box 25, Folder 442)
    - Werner, Alfred. "Art and Artists," Congress Weekly, 1957 March 25 (Box 25, Folder 443)
    - Young, Stark. "Retrospective Exhibition: Maurice Sterne," The New Republic, 1933 March 1 (Box 25, Folder 444)
  - Books
    - Salpeter, Harry. Maurice Sterne: The Maestro in Art (proof copy), undated (Box 25, Folder 445)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements (with works of Sterne)
    - Bourgeois Galleries, 1922, undated (Box 25, Folder 446)
    - City Art Museum of St. Louis, 1917 (Box 25, Folder 447)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 448)
    - Hirschl and Adler Galleries, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 449)
    - Junior League of Mt. Kisco, New York, undated (Box 25, Folder 450)
    - Milch Galleries (Exhibition announcements), 1934 (Box 25, Folder 451)
    - Montross Gallery, 1915-1916 (Box 25, Folder 452)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 453)
    - Phillips Memorial Gallery, 1948, undated (Box 25, Folder 454)
    - Reinhardt Galleries, undated (Box 25, Folder 455)
    - Riverside Museum (1947 La Tausca Art Competition) (Box 25, Folder 456)
    - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 457)
    - Wildenstein and Co., 1947 (Box 25, Folder 458)
    - Museum bulletins, 1933-1956 (Box 25, Folder 459)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - American Hebrew Who's Who, 1929-1930, undated (Box 26, Folder 460)
    - Art awards, 1930-1931, undated (Box 26, Folder 461)
    - Art of Maurice Sterne, 1916-1951, undated (Box 26, Folder 462-65)
    - Bali art, 1912-1962, undated (Box 26, Folder 466-67)
    - Carnegie Institute Competition, 1929 (Box 26, Folder 468)
    - Hawaiian Pineapple Company, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 469)
    - Honolulu Academy of Arts, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 470)
    - Justice Department murals, 1935-1941 (Box 26, Folder 471-73)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1917, undated (Box 26, Folder 474)
    - Museum of Modern Art retrospective, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 475)
    - The New Society, 1930, undated (Box 26, Folder 476)
    - Obituaries (Sterne), 1957 (Box 26, Folder 477)
    - Reproductions of Sterne's Art, 1929-1954, undated (Box 26, Folder 478)
    - Rogers-Kennedy Memorial, 1929-1955, undated (Box 26, Folder 479-80)
    - Sculpture of Maurice Sterne, 1922-1957, undated (Box 27, Folder 481)
    - Sterne exhibitions, 1915-1962 (Box 27, Folder 482-89)
    - Vera Sterne, 1929-1931 (Box 27, Folder 490)
    - Miscellaneous, 1915-1962 (Box 27, Folder 491-94)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1960, undated (Box 27, Folder 495)
- Other Papers, 1933-1963; Series VI; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series VI, Other Papers, is arranged alphabetically by author or title.
  - Auslander, Joseph and Audry. "Article of Faith", 1939 (Box 28, Folder 496)
  - Hare, E. S. [?] untitled manuscript ("Cats"), undated (Box 28, Folder 497)
  - Lewisohn, Samuel. "A Note on Roualt", 1933 July 5 (Box 28, Folder 498)
  - "Maurice Sterne and His Time", undated (Box 28, Folder 499)
  - Moore, Irene. Dramatized translation of Anna Karenina, undated (Box 28, Folder 500)
  - Unidentified application for art scholarship, undated (Box 28, Folder 501)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954-1963, undated (Box 28, Folder 502)
- 2000 Addition, 1903-1940; Series VII; 0.63; (2 boxes) + 1 art
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subdivisions: Financial Papers, Correspondence, and Other Material.
  Series VII 200 Addition includes correspondence, financial records, and other material, including an untitled oil painting, by or relating to Maurice Sterne. Correspondence includes letters from galleries, publishers, and art patrons.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 66.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Robert Meredith, 2000.
  - Financial Papers
    - Bank statements, 1933 (Box 32, Folder 523)
    - Checkbook registers, 1933 (Box 32, Folder 524)
    - Receipts, 1930-1934, undated (Box 32, Folder 525)
    - Stocks, 1926-1933 (Box 32, Folder 526)
    - Stock statements, 1932-1933 (Box 32, Folder 527-528)
  - Correspondence
    - [Beaton,] Cecil, undated (Box 32, Folder 529)
    - Bentley, H. C., 1934 (Box 32, Folder 530)
    - Bois-Reymond, Lola du, 1931, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 531)
    - Boyesen, Bayard, 1932 Febuary 17 (Box 32, Folder 532)
    - Briarcliffe Jr. College, 1932, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 533)
    - Bruce, Edward, 1930-1934 (Box 32, Folder 534)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1930 January (Box 32, Folder 535)
    - Coates, Albert, undated (Box 32, Folder 536)
    - [Hapgood], Neith, n.y. May 25 (Box 32, Folder 537)
    - Lewisohn, Adolph; Lewisohn, Margaret, 1932, undated (Box 32, Folder 538)
    - Liveright Publishers, 1932 May 24 (Box 32, Folder 539)
    - [Luhan], Mabel Dodge, undated (Box 32, Folder 540)
    - Martin, Margaret, undated (Box 32, Folder 541)
    - Martini, Arturo, undated (Box 32, Folder 542)
    - Milch Galleries, undated (Box 32, Folder 543)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1932, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 544)
    - Neumann, J. B., 1932, undated (Box 33, Folder 545)
    - New Art Circle, 1933 (Box 33, Folder 546)
    - New Republic, undated (Box 33, Folder 547)
    - New School, 1932 August 5 (Box 33, Folder 548)
    - Stein, Leo, 1929-1933, undated (Box 33, Folder 549)